A Finding Aid to the Gustave Harrow legal records relating to the Estate of Mark Rothko AAA.harrgust2
Archives of American Art
- General files, 1957-1981; Series 1; 23.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-24
  - Levine - Permission to Appeal, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Telephone Nos., 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mark Rothko Foundation 1979 Minutes & Correspondence, 1970, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Attorney for Foundation, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Foundation Election - Diary Notes (& see Gen. Diary Notes 3-24-76 - 9-21-76), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Rothko's Papers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Ferber, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Foundation Purposes - Relevence, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Goldwater - Subpoenaed Papers, 1972-1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Goldwater, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Rothko Foundation (& New Amendment) Purposes, 1979-1981 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Reis - Dickler - Mel - Foundation (Memo) & Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Foundation Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Charitable Foundation Reports & Expenses - Grants 01-62-53, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Expenses Etc., 1976 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Greenspoon, 1973-1976 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Foundation By-Laws Etc., 1969-1970, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Meeting - June 8, July 15 & Following, 1972, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Foundation Meeting Feb 2 '77, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Election of Directors Etc. & Following, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Foundation Minutes May 14 1976 - 1976 Election Etc. (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Foundation Meeting and FF Apr 7, 1977 May 9, 1977, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Goldwater Letter (10-14-70) & Dickler & Foundation, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Asch Dec. Foundation Proc. - Decision 1-16-77, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
  - Gustave Harrow Affadavit 1-13-76 - Letters of Administration, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Foundation Pro. - Reply Affadavit Gustave Harrow 12-23-76, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Gustave Harrow Affadavit 12-17-76, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - Foundation Proc. Gustave Harrow Affadavit, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Affadavit of Gustave Harrow, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Affadavit of Gustave Harrow Dec 17, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Examination - Levine 12-1-76, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Examination & Doc. - Woodbury, Thomas C., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Levine - Copies of Docs., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Wilder & Sirchia - Copies of Docs., 1976 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Examinations - Wilder, Clinton, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Wilder & Sirchia - Copies of Docs. - for Wilder EBT, 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - Wilder & Sirchia - Copies of Docs., 1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Wilder - General, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Examination - Sirchia, Gerard - Nov 12, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Rothko - Lower Court Dec., undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Decisions, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Court of Appeals Decision, 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
  - Bills of Cost - A.G. Notes, 1974-1978 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Out-Going Execs.' Accounting, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Objections - to Accounting - Final Acct. 1970-1976 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Tax Proceedings, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Tax Assessment Etc., 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Reis Assets Etc., 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 15-16)
  - Bankruptcy (Reis) Fees, 1981 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - (Rothko) Bankruptcy Settlement, 1980-1981 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
  - Reis' Bankruptcy Proceedings and Transcripts, 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Fees and Restraints vs Reis and Stamos, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Legal Fees, 1976-1979 (Box 23, Folder 6-10)
  - Fee & 5-3.3 - Decision, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Fee Correspondence - Copy, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 12-13)
  - Payment & Judgement - Return of Pictures, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Bond & Return of Pictures, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Enforcement of Decree Date of Sale v. Appreciation Values, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - MOMA Proceeding, 1974-1978 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Guggenheim Exhibition Rothko, Mark Surrogate Court NY Co. 3-7-77 Special, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Retrospective Articles Etc., 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Guggenheim Lists, 1973-1978 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Lists of Rothko Paintings, 1970-1972 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Eisenberg v. Rothko, 1978-1979 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Dickler EBT - Notes & Rich Motion & Mel - Karelsen Case EBT Dickler - New Evid., 1977 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - S/B Slips - Stock Book - Karelsen Case EBT - New Evid., 1977 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Karelsen Case - EBT Dickler - New Evid in Karelsen - Kate vs. Karelsen & Saidenberg Not in Index Cards - Not in Reis Bankruptcy - Dickler's Dep.?, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Karelsen & Saidenberg, 1976-1978 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Greenspoon v. Foundation, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Pace - Contract, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Libel Action, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Reis v. Karelsen, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Reis v. Karelsen, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Karelsen v. James et al, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Motions, 1971-1979; Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 24-25
  Series 2 contains motions from pre-trial through the New York Supreme Court appeals. The documents are mostly photocopies. Indices are in the first folders of the series. Original sub-numbers were copied from original folders, although the significance of these is not immediately evident.
  - Index, undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Index - Motions, circa 1978 (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Prior to Motions - Notes, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - 1 - 1a, 1b, 1c, 1971, undated (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - 2 - M1, D2, F43, 1971-1972 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - 3 - M2-3, D3-4, F44-44A, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - 4 - M4, D9-10, F118, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - 5 - M5, D11, F59, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - 6 - M6-7, D6 12 13, F51-58, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - 7 - M 8,9,10,11,12,14; D68-71, D8; F120, 129, 131, 1972-1975 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - 8 - M17, D7, F118, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - 9 - D14-15, F118, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 27)
  - 10 - M18, D16, F61, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
  - 11 - M19-20, D18-19, F63 70 72, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 29)
  - 12 - M21, D16A, F52, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 30)
  - 13 - M22, D18a, F64, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 31)
  - 14 - M23-25, D27-28, F76-77, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - 15 - M26, D39-30, F80, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 33)
  - 16 - M37, D26, F81, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 34)
  - 17 - M28, D21, F65, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 35)
  - 18 - M29, D31, F84, 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 36)
  - 19 - M30, 34; D22-24; F69, 71, 72, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 37)
  - 20 - M32, D32-34a, F85, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 38)
  - 21 - M35, D35, F88, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 39)
  - 22 - M36, D38, F90, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 40)
  - 23 - M37, D39, F91, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 24 - M38, D36, F92, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 25 - M39, O40, F94, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 26 - M40, D42, F95, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 27 - M41, D43 46, F74, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 28 - M42, D44, F90, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - 29 - M43, D51, F100, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - 30 - M44-45, D52, F101, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - 31 - D49, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - 32 - D50, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - 33 - M46, D53-54, F103, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - 34 - M47, D55, F104, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - 35 - M48, D56, F105, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - 36 - M49, D57-58, F108, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - 37 - M50, D60, F109, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - 38 - M51, D59, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - 39 - D61 64, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - 40 - M52, D62, F532, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - 41 - D63, 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - 42 - D65, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - 43 - D66, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - 44 - M53, D67, F110, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - 45 - M54, D79-80, F354, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - 46 - M55-56, D78 81, F356-357, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - 47 - M57, F355, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - 48 - M57, F355, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - 49 - M10, D72, F120, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - 50 - M58, F531, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 28)
  - 51 - M59, D81a, F521, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 29)
  - 52 - M13, D73, F131, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 30)
  - 53 - M60, D816, F538, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 31)
  - 54, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 32)
  - 55 - D82, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 33)
  - 56 - M15, D74, F131, 1974-1975 (Box 25, Folder 34)
  - 57 - M61, F411 414 422, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 35)
  - 58 - M62-63 65; D84-87; F43 432, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 36)
  - 59 -M64, D88, F439, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 37)
  - 60 - M16, D75-77, F132, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 38)
  - 61 - M66, D91, F441, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 39)
  - 62 - M67, D92, F433, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 40)
  - 63 - M63-64 66 68, D89-91 93 95, F441, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 41)
  - 64 - M69, D107, F442, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 42)
  - 65 - M71, D106, F443-444, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 43)
  - 66 - M72 81, D108 434 438, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 44)
  - 67 - M73 75, D104-105, F436-437, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 45)
  - 68 - M76, D94 99, F448-449, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 46)
  - 69 - M77, D103, F451, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 47)
  - 70 - M80, F520, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 48)
  - 71 - M82, D125, F535, 1975, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 49)
  - 72 - M83, F455, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 50)
  - 73 - M84 95, D111-112 122, F458-459 466 513, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 51)
  - 74 - M85, D96 101, F460, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 52)
  - 75 - M86, F457, 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 53)
  - 76 - M87, F456, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 54)
  - 77 - M88, D110, F461, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 55)
  - 78 - M89, D115-116, F520, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 56)
  - 79 - M90, D97 102, F462, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 57)
  - 80 - M91, D119, F490-497, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 58)
  - 81 - M92, D118, F463, 1976 (Box 25, Folder 59)
  - 82 - M93, D121, 533, 1976-1977 (Box 25, Folder 60)
  - 83 - M99, D133, F523-524, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 61)
  - 84 - M96, D117, F520, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 62)
  - 85 - M97, F520, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 63)
  - 86 - M98, F525, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 64)
  - 87 - M99, D133, F523-524, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 65)
  - 88 - M101, D124, F537, 1970, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 66)
  - 89 - M102, F536, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 67)
  - 90 - M103, F530, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 68)
  - 91 - M104 106, D130, F525-528A, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 69)
  - 92 - M108, D133, F540, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 70)
  - 93 - M105, D129, F534, 1978 (Box 25, Folder 71)
  - 94, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 72)
  - 95 - M107, D132, F539, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 73)
- Decisions, 1970-1979; Series 3; 0.8 Linear feet Box 26
  Series 3 consists mostly of clippings of decision announcementss from New York Law Journal, Miscellaneous Reports and other sources. There are also copies of some decisions.
  - Index to Decisions, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - To Dismiss Petition - K. Rothko Attained Majority, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - To Dismiss Petition - Subject Matter Jurisdiction, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - To Dismiss Petition - Subject Matter Jurisdiction Appeal, 972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - For Advance Payment of Commissions Mary A. Rothko Estate, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Temporary Restraining Order, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Right of Election - To Refer to M. Midonick, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Construction Proceeding - To Dismiss or Stay, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Right of Election, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Right of Election - Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - H. Ferber Deposition, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Preliminary Injunction, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Preliminary Injunction - Appeal, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Construction Proceeding - To Substitute Attorney, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Right of Election - Substitution of Attorney, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - To Deliver Paintings - to Warehouse, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Motion for Appendix, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Kate Rothko - Permission to Change Attorneys, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Interrogatory Motions - For Protective Orders - AG Interrog. I, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - For Protective Orders - AG Interrog. II, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - For Protective Orders - AG Interrog I & II - Appeal, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - To Extend Time to Object to Interrogatories, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - To Compel Answers to Interrog. I & II, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Motion in AD to Stay - Answers to Interrog I & II, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - To Compel Answers to Interrog. I & II - Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Protective Order for AG Interrog. - Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Motion to Sever Trial - Attempt, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - 1. To Dismiss AG's Cross Petition - 2. To Vacate Notices of EBTs Served by AG, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - To Vacate Notices of EBTs - Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - To Dismiss Foundation's Appeal - To Vacate Notices of EBTs, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - To Dismiss Foundation's Appeal & for Protective Order, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - To Compel Lloyd's EBT, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - AG Deposition - for Deposition of AG, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - AG Deposition - For Deposition of AG - Appeal, 1973, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - AG Depostition - For Deposition of AG - Leave to Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 35)
  - AG Deposition - For Deposition of AG - Leave to Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - AG Deposition - For Referee - And Additional Disclosure, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - AG Disclosure - To Fix a Trial Date and a Schedule for Examinations, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 38)
  - AG Deposition - Memoranda Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 39)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - For Protective Order for Levine - Notice EBT of Marlborough, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 40)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - For Disclosure Proceedings - NY Times Article, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 41)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Referee's Opinion on EBTs: Saidenberg, Kozak, Schwartz, Karelsen, Greenspoon, Richtenthal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 42)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Greenspoon Producing - Foundation Minutes, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 43)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Strike Mag Interrogatories, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 44)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Strike for Contempt II - Names of Purchasers, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 45)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - For Levine EBT, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 46)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Draw Funds for Christopher Rothko, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 47)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Confidentiality of Interrog., 1973 (Box 26, Folder 48)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Strike Marlborough's Interrogs on AG, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 49)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Reopen EBTs - Referee's Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 50)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Conference - Submission of Briefs - Establishing Trial Date, undated (Box 26, Folder 51)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Continuation of Conference of 10/23/73, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 52)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Vacate or Modify Petitioner's Notice of Discovery - Referee Opinion, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 53)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - for Protective Order Terminating Disclosure to take Reis, Stamos, Bial & Accountants EBTs - Referee Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 54)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Referee Decision on AG Notice to Discover, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 55)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Amendment on Referee Decision on AG Notice to Discover, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 56)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - To Take EBTs of Marlborough Employees, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 57)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Referee Decision - To Have Documents Delivered, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 58)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Referee Decision on Reis Examination, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 59)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Reis Examination Amendment of Referee's Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 60)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Referee Decision Concerning Protective Order Denying Discovery and Interrogatories of Northrup, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 61)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Swetlitz Deposition - Referee Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 62)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Petitioner's Notice for Discovery - Referee's Decision, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - for Inspection of Painting - Referee Memorandum, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 64)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Rulings on Applications before B. Meyer, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 65)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Reis Interrogatories, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 66)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - For Production of Plant Inventory - Referee Decision, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 67)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - Memorandum for Examination Corrections, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 68)
  - EBTs of Foundation Directors - For Protective Order for Communications between AG and Rothko and Northrup - Referee Decision, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 69)
  - Contents Proceeding - Construance of Will, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 70)
  - Contents Proceeding - Consturance of Will Appeal, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 71)
  - Contents Proceeding - Construance of Will - To Dismiss Appeal, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 72)
  - Contents Proceeding - Construance of Will - For Leave to Appeal, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 73)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Punish Executors for Contempt, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 74)
  - Contents Proceeding - For Marlborough Non-Interference with Delivery, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 75)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Terminate Control of Clerk, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 76)
  - Contents Proceeding - Fees, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 77)
  - Contents Proceeding - Fees, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 78)
  - Contents Proceeding - Fees, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 79)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Impound Paintings - Insurance, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 80)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Quash Subpoena, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 81)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Quash Subpoena, undated (Box 26, Folder 82)
  - Contents Proceeding to Hold in Contempt, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 83)
  - Contents Proceeding - To Suspend Executors - Re: Tax Proceeding, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 84)
  - Contents Proceding - To Remove Restrictions Concerning - The Confidentiality of all Pretrial Briefs Transcript, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 85)
  - Contents Proceeding - Meyer Fee, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 86)
  - Contents Proceeding - Trial Decision for Removal, undated (Box 26, Folder 87)
  - Contents Proceeding - Restraining Order - Temp., 1975 (Box 26, Folder 88)
  - Contents Proceding - Restraining Order - Temp., 1975 (Box 26, Folder 89)
  - Contents Proceeding - For Interim Mandatory Injunction Interim Receiver, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 90)
  - Contents Proceeding - For Interim Mandatory Injunction Interim Receiver, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 91)
  - Contents Proceeding - Administrator, 1975-1976 (Box 26, Folder 92)
  - Contents Proceeding - Decree, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 93)
  - Contents Proceeding - Decree Modification, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 94)
  - Court Proceeding - To Reargue Prior Court Decision - Return of Paintings, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 95)
  - Contents Proceeding - Motion for Marlborough's Records, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 96)
  - Reis & Stamos - Stay of Enforcement - AD 1st Dept., 1976 (Box 26, Folder 97)
  - To Stay Enforcement - Reis & Stamos - AD 1st Draft Motion to Reargue, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 98)
  - Leave to Appeal - Motion for Stay of Enforcement Reis & Stamos, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 99)
  - To Modify Order for Stay - Reis & Stamos - To Extend Time to Perfect Appeal, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 100)
  - To Modify Order for Stay - Reis & Stamos - To Extend Time to Perfect Appeal, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 101)
  - To Stay Enforcement without Bond - Levine - AD 1st Draft, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 102)
  - To Stay Enforcement - Levine - AD 1st Draft - Motion to Reargue, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 103)
  - For Leave to Appeal for Stay of Enforcement - Levine - AD 1st Dept., 1976 (Box 26, Folder 104)
  - To Modify Order for Stay - Levine - Extend Time to Perfect Appeal, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 105-106)
  - To Stay Enforcement - Marlborough & Lloyd - AD 1st Draft, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 107)
  - To Appeal Marlborough's Stays, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 108)
  - For Stay in Enforcement and Canada Records - AG Motion, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 109)
  - Levine - For Stay in Enforcement and Canada Records to Strike, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 110)
  - Levine - For Contempt, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 111)
  - Levine - To Punish for Contempt - Pictures Shipped after Injunction, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 112)
  - Levine - For Marlborough to Report Sales, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 113)
  - Levine - Bond, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 114)
  - Levine - To Limit the Record, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 115)
  - Levine - Motion for Relief, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 116)
  - Levine Motion for Relief - Appeal, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 117)
  - Levine - To Punish for Contempt, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 118)
  - Levine - Dates for Appendices & Points, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 119)
  - Levine - Accounting Procedure - Protective Order for Reis, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 120)
  - Levine - Accounting Proceeding - Reis Protective Order, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 121)
  - Levine Accounting Proceeding - Protective Order, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 122)
  - Levine - To Extend Time to Serve Points, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 123)
  - Levine - Foundation Elections, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 124)
  - Levine - Trial of Removal - Appeal, undated (Box 26, Folder 125)
  - Guggenheim Exhibit, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 126)
  - For Leave to Appeal - Motion for Levine Relief, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 127)
  - Trial of Removal - Court of Appeal Decision, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 128)
  - Pace, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 129)
  - Prizel v.Karelsen & Saidenberg - Settlement Agreement, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 130)
  - Costs & Disbursements, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 131)
  - Decree - Court of Appeals - Recovery of Costs, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 132)
  - Appeal - Reis - From Bill of Costs Awarded in 9/5/78 Order, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 133)
  - Eisenberg v. Rothko - To Vacate the Dismissal Action, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 134)
  - Fees - & 5-33, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 135)
  - Notes on Meyer's Decisions, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 136)
  - Reis v. Karelsen, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 137)
  - Reis Bankruptcy, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 138)
- Appeals Documents, 1972-1979; Series 4; 4.3 Linear feet Boxes 26-31
  Arranged in original order; folder titles were transcribed exactly from original folders
  Series 4 contains files originally designated "M" consisting of motions, plus New York Supreme court, and New York Supreme Court Appellate Division documents. Additionally there are appendices, briefs, and depositions.
  - M Files - Motion To Dismiss - K.Rothko Attained Majority, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 139)
  - M Files - Motion to Dismiss - Subject Matter Jurisdiction, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 140)
  - M Files - Motion to Dismiss - Subject Matter Jurisdiction - Appeal, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 141)
  - M Files - Election, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 142)
  - M Files - H. Ferber Depostion, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 143)
  - M Files - Motion Temp. Restraining Order, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 144)
  - M Files - Preliminary Injunction - Appeal, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 145)
  - M Files - Record on Appeal, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 146)
  - M Files - Brief for the Attorney General, Cross-Petition-Respondent, undated (Box 26, Folder 147)
  - M Files - Answering Brief and Appendix of the Attorney General of State of New York as Respondent, undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - M Files - Motion to Dismiss - Construction Proceeding, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding, 1972-1974 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motin to Punish for Contempt, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motion for Stay of Decree Pending Appeal, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motin to Dismiss Appeal, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - M Files - Construction Proceeding - Motion for Marlborough Non-Interference, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 7)